Wow. That ripped.
它會扯破衣服
That ripped real nice!
一點也不含糊
How many times do I have to tell you? You turn and slide.
你要我說幾次？要側身滑出來
Turn and slide.
側身滑出來
You don't turn and slide.
不是側身滑出來
You throw it out!
是把它扔出去
I get tetanus shots every time I get dressed!
我每次穿衣服 都得打破傷風預防針
We're not throwing it out. I built it with my own hands!
不能扔掉，這是我親手釘的
How about we sell it?
好，那賣掉呢？
All right.
好吧
But you'll have to tell them.
不過你得告訴它們
Can we stick you in another cabinet? They seem all right with it!
你們可以搬個家嗎？ 看來它們沒意見
The One with the Cat
本集播出：「靈貓」
rainystar壓制iPod-MP4
Hey,why did the chicken fall out of the tree?
雞為什麼不會從樹下掉下來？
Why?
為什麼？
Because you have doody on your head.
因為頭上有翅膀
Yeah,it was funnier when Ben told it.
班說就很好笑
Hey,Monica. It's Chip.
摩妮卡，我是奇普 漂亮！
Who's Chip?
誰是奇普？
It was good running into you today.
很高興今天遇見你
My number is 555-9323. Give me a call.
我的電話是5559323 打給我，就這樣
"Chip" is Chip Matthews.
奇普就是奇普馬修斯
The guy who took Rachel to the prom? Why's he calling you?
瑞秋的高中舞會舞伴？ 他打給你幹什麼？
Because I ran into him at the bank. He is still so cute.
我在銀行遇見他，他還是好帥
You're so lucky! He's like the most popular guy in school!
你好幸運 他是全校最紅的男生
I know!
我知道
Chip? Hi,it's Monica.
奇普？我是摩妮卡
好…好
好
Oh,my God! We just had the best conversation!
好，再見 天哪，我們聊得好愉快
I was just leaving.
我正要走
Good.
好
I've got a report to read.
我要看報告
It's eight pages. I hope I don't fall asleep.
有八頁，但願我不會睡著
Why? Did you write it?
為什麼？是你寫的？
Look at that!
你看看
Chip Matthews called. I wonder what he wants.
奇普馬修斯打電話來 不曉得有什麼事
Well,actually....
其實…
I bet he sensed that I was ready to have sex with another guy.
他一定感應到 我可以跟別的男人上床了
Why don't you give him a call?
那你何不打給他？
好啊
-Are you sure you want to hear this? -I'm sure.
你真的想聽？ 真的
Chip! Hi,it's Rachel.
奇普，我是瑞秋
Rachel Greene.
瑞秋葛林
You left me a message?
你留言給我？
Yes,you did. My roommate wrote it down.
你有，我的室友記下來了
Monica Geller?
摩妮卡蓋勒？
Oh,that's right!
原來如此
He called to ask out Monica.
他是要約摩妮卡
That's got to be embarrassing.
真是尷尬
Dumb drunken bitch
醉醺醺的白癡賤人
Thank you!
謝謝
Here's a question.
請問一下
Where'd you get the "finest oak east of the Mississippi"?
密西西比以東 最好的橡木傢俱在哪裡？
First tell us where you got the prettiest lace in the land.
你先說 全國最漂亮的蕾絲在哪裡
It's your ad.
這是你們的廣告
Looks good?
不賴吧？
"Stunning entertainment center,fine
「高級視聽娛樂櫃，精緻…」
Fine ltalian craftsmanship."
「精緻意大利手工」
You're selling the entertainment center?
天哪，你們要賣娛樂櫃？
Why? I love it.
為什麼？我喜歡那個櫃子
-You want it? -No.
你們要嗎？ 不要
Gepetto?
「名家手藝」？
Five thousand dollars?
「定價5千」？
Are you insane?
你瘋了嗎？
The ad alone cost $300.
登廣告就要3百
I'm changing it to $50 or your best offer.
我要改成50元或再議
What kind of profit is that? And you call yourself an accountant?
那有什麼利潤可言？ 你也配當會計師？
我不是
What do you do?
那你是什麼？
I can't believe you don't know.
你居然不知道我幹哪一行
I actually don't know.
我也不知道 是不是什麼…
Oh,my God,no! Shoo,kitty!
天哪，不要，走開 不要…
There's a kitty in my guitar case.
阿甘，我的吉他盒裡有一隻貓
Everyone's gonna want one.
噓…其他人都想要
Come on,you!
給我過來
Crazy!
真是的
-Oh,my God! -What?
天哪 什麼？
Nothing.
沒事
What's wrong?
怎麼了？
I just have this really strong feeling that this cat is my mother.
我只是有一股強烈的感覺 這隻貓是我媽
The mom you met in Montauk? She was a cat?
莫陶克那個媽媽？ 她是一隻貓？
That makes the fact that she owns beach-front property all the more impressive.
而她居然擁有濱海小屋
No. She was a human lady.
不，她是一個人
This is the spirit of my mom,Lilly. The one that killed herself.
這是莉莉媽媽的靈魂 自殺的那個
Have you been taking your grandmother's glaucoma medicine again?
是她變成一隻貓 還是你又偷吃外婆的青光眼藥
No,Dr. Skeptismo.
沒有，疑心病博士
I'm sure. First of all,there's the feeling.
我很肯定 第一，我有這個感覺
And for another, she went into my guitar case...
還有，她跑進我的吉他盒裡
...which is lined with orange felt.
它的襯裡是橘色的
My mother's favorite fish was orange roughy.
我媽最喜歡的魚是橘棘鯛
Cats like fish.
貓喜歡吃魚
You had me with orange felt.
聽到橘色襯裡我就信了
Hi,Mommy!
媽
I haven't seen this smile in 17 years.
我17年沒看到這個笑容了
-Phoebe's mom's got a huge pair of -Let it go!
菲比的媽有兩顆好大的… 算了吧
When were you going to tell me that you're dating Chip?
你什麼時候要告訴我 你要跟奇普約會？
Now?
現在？
Can I go out with him?
我跟他約會沒關係吧？
No. I can't believe you'd want to after what he did to me.
當然有關係 他那樣對我耶
That thing at the prom?
你是說舞會的事？
I couldn't find him for hours! He was having sex with Amy Welsh!
摩妮卡，我2個小時找不到他 他跑去跟艾美威許做愛
That was in high school. How can it still bother you?
那是高中的事 你怎麼還會在意？
Oh,yeah,you're right,Moni-cow.
說得也是，莫母豬
Okay,I hear you.
我懂了
Why do you have to go out with Chip?
你為什麼偏要跟奇普約會？
We went to different schools.
我們的高中不一樣
We went to the same school.
少來，我們上同一所高中
You went to one where you were popular.
你在高中是風雲人物
You rode on Chip's motorcycle and wore his letterman jacket.
你坐奇普的摩托車 穿他的特優選手外套
I went to one where I wore a band uniform that was specially made.
我穿的是特製的樂隊制服
They had that specially made?
那是特製的？
It was a Home Ec project.
那是家政課的作業之一
Oh,my God! They said it was for the mascot.
天哪 他們說那是給吉祥物穿的
Back then I thought that I'd never get to go out with a Chip Matthews.
那時候我以為 我永遠不可能跟奇普約會
Now he's called me up and asked me out.
現在他打來約我
The fat girl inside me really wants to go. I owe her this.
我心中那個胖女孩真的很想去 這是我欠她的
I never let her eat.
我從不讓她盡情的吃
-You go out with him. -Really?
你去吧 真的？
If possible,could you leave him and have sex with another guy?
如果可以，你能不能丟下他 去跟別人做愛？
I'll try.
我試試看
Any luck getting rid of the entertainment center?
娛樂櫃賣得怎樣？
There were a couple calls, but they won't work out.
昨晚有幾通詢問電話 但我都覺得不可行
Joey has a very careful screening process.
喬伊有一套嚴格的篩選過程
Not everyone is qualified to own wood and nails.
並非每個人都適合擁有木製品
Stop it!
別掙扎了
She keeps trying to get away. Just like when she was alive.
她一直想跑走 跟在世時一樣
How long is your mom going to be with us?
你媽要跟我們在一起多久？
I'm not sure.
我不確定
I guess until she gets used to the fact that there's...
直到她能接受我有了…
...a new mom.
新媽媽吧
Now she's worried that she'll be replaced.
她很擔心會被取代
That's not going to happen,is it?
才不會呢，對不對？
I have to go make a call.
我去房裡回個電話
Why not use this phone?
怎麼不在這裡打？
I'm returning a call from a certain mom at the B-E-A-C-H.
我要打給住在（海邊）的媽媽
I just spelled the wrong word.
我說反了
Anyway,I don't want to do it in front of someone with a tail.
我不想在有尾巴的人面前打
Hey,you swore you would never tell.
你發誓不說的
So am I crazy,or does Phoebe's mom remind anyone else of a cat?
是我瘋了，還是有人也覺得 菲比的媽像一隻貓？
Ross,don't start.
羅斯，別提了 拜託
You actually believe there's a woman inside that cat?
你們真的相信 那隻貓是一個女人變的？
I believe it.
我相信
No,you don't.
你才不信
Yes,I do.
我信
No,you
你才不…
You know what?
你知道嗎？
You won't suck me into this.
我不會跟你爭辯
Sure I will. Because you always have to be right.
你會 你總是要說服別人
I do not always have Okay,okay.
我才沒有… 好
Jurassic Park could happen.
「侏羅紀公園」是有可能的
And you know what? Actually, I do think Kirk was smarter than Spock.
還有 我覺得蟑螂比恐龍聰明
You were kidding about the Kirk-Spock-thing,though,right?
剛才那句是開玩笑吧？
That's pretty nice.
還不賴嘛
"Pretty nice"?
還不賴？
Pardon my roommate. He wanted to marry this.
原諒我的室友 他簡直想娶它過門
We don't have $50. But would you trade for it?
我們沒有50塊錢 你們願意交換嗎？
We got a canoe.
我們有一艘獨木舟
I don't think we need a canoe.
我們不需要獨木舟
You got to take it.
你們一定要收下獨木舟
Just take the entertainment center.
你們就把櫃子搬走吧
Then when you get home, throw the canoe away.
等你們到家，再把獨木舟扔掉
We're not throwing it away. I built it.
想都別想，那是我親手造的
Good for you!
幹得好！
（中央咖啡館）
You won't believe what I found on a telephone pole.
你們看我在電線桿上發現什麼
Look familiar?
眼熟嗎？
Apparently Phoebe's mother also goes by the name "Julio."
顯然菲比的母親也叫胡立歐
Wait a minute. This is not the same cat. This cat's only this big.
不一樣吧，這只只有這麼大
A little girl's looking for this cat. Know what that means?
有個小女孩在找這隻貓 知道這代表什麼嗎？
Yeah! $200 reward split five ways!
知道，五個人平分2百元賞金
Do we have to tell her?
要告訴她嗎？
-Yes,we do. -But it's made her so happy.
當然要告訴她 但她現在好開心
Little girl misses her cat.
想念貓咪的小女孩
Crazy lady thinks her mother is in a cat.
覺得貓是母親轉世的瘋婆子
I have to go have dinner with my son.
好，我要去跟我兒子吃飯
Can I trust that when you see Phoebe, you will tell her?
你們見到菲比會告訴她吧？
會
Thank you.
謝謝
I hate when Ross is right.
我最討厭羅斯說對了
He is right,isn't he?
他說得對，對吧？
This might be one time when he's wrong.
搞不好這一次他錯了
-You think? -Oh,no. He's right.
是嗎？ 不，他說得對
About your mom.
菲比，關於你的母親… 怎樣？
How's that going?
你們處得好嗎？
So great. We took a nap together today.
棒呆了，我們今天一起睡午覺
Mom fell asleep on my tummy and purred.
媽在我肚子上睡著還打呼
That's so sweet.
真溫馨
I'm gonna get some coffee.
我去點咖啡
What'd you say,Joe? I'll be right there.
喬伊你說什麼？我馬上過去
I just feel so....
菲比 我覺得好…
-All right! -I'm coming already!
知道了啦 馬上來
Not yet,not yet,not yet!
還沒還沒還沒…
-Hello,Chip. -How you doing?
奇普 瑞秋，你好嗎？
I'm great!
很好
Got a great job. I have wonderful friends.
我有一份好工作，一群好朋友
Though I'm not seeing anyone now, I've never felt better about myself.
雖然現在沒有男朋友 卻對自己很滿意
So,Monica ready yet?
摩妮卡好了嗎？
She'll be out in a second.
她馬上就好
So,Chip,how's Amy Welsh?
奇普，艾美威許好嗎？
Amy Welsh? I haven't seen her since
艾美威許？我們自從…
So,Monica about ready?
摩妮卡快好了嗎？
-Wow,you look great. -Thanks.
你好漂亮 謝謝
-Well,you guys have fun. -Catch you later.
好好去玩吧 再聯絡
Bye,Chip.
奇普再見
-Are you sure you're okay about this? -Actually
你真的不在意？ 其實…
Okay,great.
太好了
This is the unit for you.
買這個櫃子就對了
Sturdy construction, tons of storage.
堅固耐用，容量超大
Some big enough to fit a grown man.
甚至塞得進一個大人
-What? -Yeah,I got in there myself once.
什麼？ 對，我就進去過一次
My roommate bet me $5 I couldn't.
我的室友賭5元說我進不去
Then he stuck a board through the handles and locked me in.
然後在門把上塞棍子把我關住
It was funny till I felt like it was a coffin.
起先很好玩，後來感覺像棺材
No,you can't fit in there. It's not deep enough.
你才進不去，它不夠深
Oh,yeah?
是嗎？
If I can't...
要是我進不去…
...I'll knock $5 off the price.
就少算你5塊錢
All right,you have yourself a deal.
就這麼說定 好
See? I told you.
你看，我就說吧
Sometimes I come in here just to get away from it.
有時我會進進出出的玩
Hey,a nickel!
有5分錢
Here we are.
到了
You still have the Chipper!
天哪，你的奇車還在
The what?
什麼？
That's what we called your motorcycle in high school.
那是你的車子在高中的外號
A motorcycle's a chopper.
摩托車也叫機車
And you're Chip.
而你叫奇普
Never mind.
沒事
I think it's cute.
真可愛
A lipper from Chipper.
奇普親親
Are you still in touch with anyone?
你還有跟哪些同學聯絡？
There's Rachel...
有瑞秋，還有…
...and that's it. How about you?
就這樣，你呢？
I still hang with Simens and Zana. I see Spindler,Levine,Kelly.
我還在跟西門斯、薩納混 也常跟史賓、萊文、凱利見面
I run into Goldie...
三不五時會遇見高第
...Stick,Brown,Sulkov,McGuire...
史迪、布朗、蘇卡夫、麥奎爾
...J.T.,Beardsley.
傑弟、畢斯利
Is that all?
就這樣？
After high school, you kind of lose touch.
畢了業都會失去聯絡
I ran into Richard Dorfman.
我有遇見李察多夫曼
-How is he? -Me and Simens gave him a wedgie.
他好嗎？ 不太好，被我和西門斯敲竹槓
Isn't he an architect?
他不是建築師嗎？
They still wear underwear.
建築師也要穿內褲
Oh,my God!
天哪！
What?
怎麼了？
Are you all right?
你還好嗎？ 還好
What happened?
怎麼回事？
Oh,man,he promised he wouldn't take the chairs!
他答應不拿沙發椅的
How were you locked in? Where the hell is all of our stuff?
你怎麼會被關進去？ 我們的東西呢？
This guy came by to look at the unit...
有一個人來看櫃子
...and he said it won't fit a grown man.
他說它塞不下一個大人
So you got in voluntarily?
所以你自願進去？
I was trying to make a sale!
我想把櫃子賣出去
If I ever run into him, you know what I'll do?
要是讓我碰上他 你猜我會怎樣？
Bend over?
把屁股翹起來？
And then Zana just let one rip!
薩納乾脆讓另一個破掉
Not that I don't enjoy talking about high school...
我不是不喜歡回憶往事
...because I do.
我喜歡
Maybe we can talk about something else.
但我們可以聊點別的
I don't know where you work.
像你，我還不曉得你的工作
-You know where I work. -I do?
你知道啊 我知道？
The movie theater. You used to come in all the time.
電影院啊，你以前常來
Still at the Multiplex?
你還在影城做事？
Like I'd give up that job!
我怎麼可能換工作
Free popcorn and candy anytime I want?
隨時都有爆米花和糖果可吃
I can get you posters.
我可以幫你拿海報
Thanks,I'm set.
謝謝，不用了
Oh,you know who came in the other night? Peters.
你猜那天誰來了？彼得斯
Told me he just went out with Leslie Maskin. Got to third base.
他說他剛才跟女朋友上了三壘
Do you still live with your parents?
你還住在家裡？
Yeah,but I can stay out as late as I want.
對，但是沒有門禁
You know,with all of our stuff gone, the unit doesn't seem that big.
少了別的東西 櫃子就沒那麼大了
Why couldn't he have been a kidnapper.
那個人怎麼不是綁匪？
They really got you guys. Your TV,the chairs.
他們還真是大搬家 電視、沙發椅
Your microwave,the stereo.
微波爐、音響
Man,he took the five of spades!
天哪，他把黑桃5拿走了
No,here it is.
在這裡
Oh,my God! What happened?
天哪！怎麼了？
Joey was born,and then 28 years later, I was robbed!
喬伊出生 28年後，我被搶了
So how was your date?
怎麼樣？
Well,I always wanted to go out with Chip in high school.
我高中時一直想跟奇普約會
Tonight,I actually went out with Chip in high school.
今晚 我真的跟高中的奇普約會了
Honey,I'm sorry.
真可惜
Not only did I get to go out with Chip...
不會，我不但跟奇普約了會
...I got to dump Chip.
我還甩了他
-That's so great! -I know.
太棒了 我知道
What did the insurance company say?
保險公司怎麼說？
They said,"You don't have insurance. Stop calling us."
他們說 「你們沒投保，別再打來了」
You didn't tell her?
你們沒有告訴她？
Okay,fine.
好吧
菲比
Listen...
聽我說
...this cat belongs to a little girl.
這隻貓是一個小女孩的
There are flyers all over the place.
路上帖滿了尋貓啟事
I'm sorry,sweetie.
對不起
We can take her back with you if you want.
我們可以陪你把貓送回去
But,you know,she chose to find me.
但是她選擇來找我
I have to respect her decision,right?
我得尊重她的決定，對吧？
-That's a good call. -That's right.
有道理 沒錯
Enough is enough.
不對，別再鬧了
I'm sorry you feel guilty about spending time with your new mom.
我很遺憾你跟新媽媽在一起 會有罪惡感
But this isn't your old mom.
但這不是你的舊媽媽
This is a cat.
這是一隻貓
Julio the cat.
它叫胡立歐
Not Mom! Cat.
不是媽媽，是貓
Ross,how many parents have you lost?
羅斯，你失去過幾個父母？
None.
零個
Then you don't know how it feels when one of them comes back.
那你就無法體會 其中一個回來的感覺，對吧？
I believe this is my mother.
我相信這是我的母親
Even if I'm wrong,who cares?
就算不是又怎樣？
Just be a friend,okay? Be supportive.
你就當個好朋友，支持我
I'm sorry.
對不起
Okay.
好
I don't know what to say.
我不知道該說什麼
You could say...
你可以...
...you're sorry to her mom.
...向她的媽媽道歉
I think she would like that.
我想她會接受
Come here. Here,come here.
乖，過來
Mrs. Buffay?
布非太太？
Sorry about what I said.
我為我說的話道歉
It was insensitive of me to say...
我實在很傷人
...that you were just a cat...
說你只是一隻貓
...when,clearly,you are also...
很顯然的，你也是…
...the reincarnated spirit...
我朋友的母親…
...of my friend's mother.
靈魂轉世
Thank you.
謝謝你
We both forgive you.
我們都原諒你
What will you do about the little girl?
那個小女孩怎麼辦？
Listen.
好，聽我說
Mom,I hope you know you still mean a lot to me.
媽，你對我還是很重要
You're welcome to come back anytime.
你隨時都可以回來
If she'd come back as a couch, we'd really appreciate it.
要是她可以變成一張沙發 我們會很感激
Come on. I'll take you home.
走吧，我帶你回家
-I'll go with you. -Me too.
我跟你去 我也去
I got an extra futon.
我有多的蒲團
Dude,you don't have to brag. We got nothing here.
你拽個屁啊，我們什麼都沒有
謹此紀念桃樂絲考夫曼
You know....
說真的…
It's peaceful out here.
這裡真幽靜